Alice and Bob each have a Calliope
The Calliopes, when you switch them on they start sending beeps.
And, if you are far away,
That´s Bob quite far far away
Alice is beeping but there is nothing
And there is nothing received because, basically, she is on her own.
So she says, ok, is there anyone close by?
No? So it should be empty, ..., empty thing (the received messages)
But if for whatever reasons
Alice and Bob get close
sorry Bob!
then, all of a sudden,
they should be able to actually receive the messages from each other
that was like something has been received by Bob (the arrow down sign)
because he was close to Alice.
The messages change in every epoch
and you can see, Alice has received something from Bob
Ok, so now let's imagine that Bob actually goes far away again..
and Alice keeps beeping through the day
but now since Bob is far away
it´s just like, not picking up any signals
the epochs keep changing
At the end of the day we have each of them at home
Alice gets infected
And decides to tell the hospital that maybe she is infected
So what she can do is to say:
Hospital, these are the messages that I've been beeping along the day
so I´m going to send them to the hospital
Today I beeped these numbers, number 13, 12 and 11
But typically those would be random numbers
And the hospital can say:
I have received that somebody with codes 13, 12 and 11 has COVID
There is nothing about the location, it´s just only the numbers (being transmitted)
And Bob can say:
Maybe I should check if I have been in contact today with somebody that has the virus
He can ask the hospital
and the hospital can broadcast things like,
these are the numbers that we know of people that have the virus
so Bob can say:
These are the numbers that I had (received from others in close contact)
13, ok, that was not a problem
so that´s "All clear"
It goes through the codes because he was not in contact with the person who broadcasted 13 (he was far away)
... but then there was one code which was red
which means, he has to stay at home
And that´s just using Calliope, Bluetooth
and some free time
Remember, Stay at home!